<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>publication on Floris den Hengst&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/tags/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in publication on Floris den Hengst&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:14:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://florisdenhengst.github.io/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RL for Real Life Poster</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-at-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:14:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-at-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming weekend will be a virtual conference on reinforcement learning (RL) in real-life.
It is of great interest to me primarily due to its program but also due to its organisation.
The virtual conference consists of two panel sessions and a virtual `poster&amp;rsquo; session with pre-recorded videos. There is a slack workspace for discussion, and questions to the panelists can be submitted up-front. Poster presenters are to host their own video channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Personalization: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-pers-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:22:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-pers-survey/</guid>
      <description>Reinforcement learning (RL) is becoming an increasingly popular tool to tackle hairy problems using data. A nice example of such a hairy problem is personalization. Personalization refers to a task central to many applications of data science and machine learning: to change a system so that its personal relevance to an individual or category of individuals is increased.
Although RL is becoming more popular, a clear overview of different RL approaches within personalization is lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collecting User Satisfaction Ratings for Dialogue Systems</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/high-quality-ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 11:35:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/high-quality-ratings/</guid>
      <description>Mickey, a master student I was co-supervising, recently published a paper based on his thesis work in ACM&amp;rsquo;s Conference for Human Information Interaction and Retrieval. His work focused on interfaces for collecting high-quality user satisfaction ratings for dialogue systems.
User satisfaction is an important indicator in the design, evaluation and adaptation of dialogue systems. Establishing user satisfaction ratings for conversation-based systems, however, remains challenging. User questionnaires may yield biased results and typically have low response rates (~1%).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Dialogue Management</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/personalized-dm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 10:31:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/personalized-dm/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I explained how reinforcement learning (RL) can be used to make chatbots better from its experience with users. RL allows chatbots to learn what to say by interacting with users. This allows for chatbots to tailor their behavior to preferences of groups of individuals, e.g. to personalize the interaction. I recently presented our paper on this topic, specifically on personalized dialog management at the Web Intelligence conference in Thessaloniki.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>