<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pomdp on Floris den Hengst&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/tags/pomdp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pomdp on Floris den Hengst&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:22:30 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://florisdenhengst.github.io/tags/pomdp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Personalization: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-pers-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:22:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-pers-survey/</guid>
      <description>Update 2020-06-27: this paper was presented as a `poster&#39;(video) at the RL for Real Life virtual Conference. Read more here.
Reinforcement learning (RL) is becoming an increasingly popular tool to tackle hairy problems using data. A nice example of such a hairy problem is personalization. Personalization refers to a task central to many applications of data science and machine learning: to change a system so that its personal relevance to an individual or category of individuals is increased.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Dialogue Management</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/personalized-dm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 10:31:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/personalized-dm/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I explained how reinforcement learning (RL) can be used to make chatbots better from its experience with users. RL allows chatbots to learn what to say by interacting with users. This allows for chatbots to tailor their behavior to preferences of groups of individuals, e.g. to personalize the interaction. I recently presented our paper on this topic, specifically on personalized dialog management at the Web Intelligence conference in Thessaloniki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Reinforcement Learning is Applied to Dialogue Control</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-dialog-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 12:41:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-dialog-management/</guid>
      <description>The value offering of most contemporary chatbot platforms consists of packaging state-of-art Automated Speech Recognition (ASR, or &amp;lsquo;speech-to-text&amp;rsquo;), Natural Language Understanding (NLU) and Voice Synthesis into a comprehensive API. The API typically also includes some programming model for dialog control such as DialogFlows&#39; Contexts and follow-up Intents and Alexa&amp;rsquo;s Dialog model. Implementing the right dialog controller is up to the developer. Figure 1 summarizes this in a diagram, with the handcrafted modules in green and with a keyboard in the top right.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
