<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Personalization on Floris den Hengst&#39;s Homepage</title>
    <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/tags/personalization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Personalization on Floris den Hengst&#39;s Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:14:18 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://florisdenhengst.github.io/tags/personalization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RL for Real Life Poster</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-at-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 21:14:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-at-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming weekend will be a virtual conference on reinforcement learning (RL) in real-life.
It is of great interest to me primarily due to its program but also due to its organisation.
The virtual conference consists of two panel sessions and a virtual `poster&amp;rsquo; session with pre-recorded videos. There is a slack workspace for discussion, and questions to the panelists can be submitted up-front. Poster presenters are to host their own video channel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcement Learning for Personalization: A Survey</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-pers-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 09:22:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/rl-for-pers-survey/</guid>
      <description>Reinforcement learning (RL) is becoming an increasingly popular tool to tackle hairy problems using data. A nice example of such a hairy problem is personalization. Personalization refers to a task central to many applications of data science and machine learning: to change a system so that its personal relevance to an individual or category of individuals is increased.
Although RL is becoming more popular, a clear overview of different RL approaches within personalization is lacking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personalized Dialogue Management</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/personalized-dm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 10:31:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/personalized-dm/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post I explained how reinforcement learning (RL) can be used to make chatbots better from its experience with users. RL allows chatbots to learn what to say by interacting with users. This allows for chatbots to tailor their behavior to preferences of groups of individuals, e.g. to personalize the interaction. I recently presented our paper on this topic, specifically on personalized dialog management at the Web Intelligence conference in Thessaloniki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Writing Course</title>
      <link>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/completed-scientific-writing-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2018 13:10:34 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://florisdenhengst.github.io/posts/completed-scientific-writing-course/</guid>
      <description>I just completed the course &amp;lsquo;Writing a Scientific Article&amp;rsquo; at the VU Language Centre. Although I joined the course thinking I knew a fair share of writing in English, I learned a great deal about scientific writing and picked up some neat tricks to improve writing. As a bonus, I got some great feedback on an survey paper on Reinforcement Learning for personalization I&amp;rsquo;m working on with some colleagues in our group</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>